Guide to the Adriana Miller papers, 1950-2010 MS2005
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Adriana Miller papers
1950-2010
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Miller, Adriana
MS2005
8.75 Linear Feet
Collection consists of administrative files, photographs, audio cassettes and video cassettes all related to the career of Adriana Miller as a dancer, entertainer, and teacher. The collection dates from 1950-2010.
Historical or Biographical Note
Adriana Miller was born in Boston, Massachusetts in the midst of the Great Depression. She studied dance at the Boston Conservatory of Music and continued her studies at the Stanley Brown Dance Studios. In 1972, Adriana opened her own school in Washington, D.C., called Adriana's Mecca of Middle Eastern Dance, where she taught dance, make-up, and skin care, as well as costume construction, and music theory classes. She also had her own troop of dancers called Adriana's Mecca of Middle Eastern Dancers. In 1979, she was recognized at the Kennedy Center for her talents and achievements. She closed her school in 1982 and retired.
Adriana returned to the dance scene in 1990. In 1992, she presented her first Middle Eastern and Mediterranean Danse Orietale Gala Review and Reunion. The following year she was inducted into the American Academy of Middle Eastern Dance Hall of Fame. In 1997, the documentary Adriana: Shadows on Yellow Silk premiered at the Mary Pickford Theater at the Library of Congress. The film chronicles Adriana's rise to fame and the role she played in the renaissance of Middle Eastern dance in Washington, D.C., as well as her personal struggles, retirement, and return to the dance scene.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Adriana Miller, 1998 donaton and also November 11, 2014 (2014.041).
Collection Scope and Content
The Adriana Miller Collection consists of administrative files, photographs, phonographs audio cassettes and video cassettes all related to the career of Adriana Miller as a dancer, entertainer, and teacher. The collection dates from 1950-2010 and is part of the Dance Archives of the Greater Washington Region. The Archives was established in 1993 by Nancy Diers Johnson, Ed.D., Associate Professor of Dance, and the Gelman Library of The George Washington University. The Dance Archives of the Greater Washington Region collects, preserves and makes accessible the documentary heritage of all forms and types of dance.
Collection Organization
Arranged in four series: Administrative files, Photographs, Audio and visual materials, Phonographs.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Photographs; Audiotapes; Dancers; Dance schools; Videotapes; Dance; Washington (D.C.); Miller, Adriana; Adriana's Mecca of Middle Eastern Dance (Washington, D.C.)
- Administrative files, 1964-2010; MS2005 Series 1
  Arrangement
  Organized into 3 subseries: 2008 donation, Companies, Publicity and dance materials
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of brochures, articles, research, correspondence, flyers, press releases, programs, and reviews all related to Adriana Miller's career as a dancer, entertainer, and teacher. The dates covered include 1964-2010.
  - 2008 Donation, 1964-2000; Series 1 Subseries 1
    Scope and Contents
    This subseries contains materials that were included in the original donation made in 2008. The dates covered include 1964-2000.
    Arranged alphabetically.
    - Brochures, 1992-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and Articles, 1964-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1967-2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Flyers, 1968-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Series: Arranged alphabetically.
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Press Releases, 1992-1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Programs, 1978-2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Reviews, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Companies, 1973-1981; Series 1 Subseries 2
    This subseries includes material related to various companies that Adriana Miller did business with while operating her dance school. It also contains information about other dance schools. The dates covered include 1973-1981.
    - Ali Ba Ba Company, 1976; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Baumgarten's, 1979; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Belly Dancing Schools, undated; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Butane Products Corp. - Flamex, 1974-1976; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Casablanca Import-Export Company, 1977; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Catalogs Unlimited Inc., 1976; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Chris Kalogerson Music, undated; Series 1Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Dance Schools, High Schools, Colleges, 1976; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Discs Araf - Records Music of the Ghawazee, 1976-1980; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Eddie Kochak, 1975-1980; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Farida Drums, 1976; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Folk Dance Teachers, 1978; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Freeman-McFarlin Potteries, 1979-1980; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Gallery Creations, Inc., 1976; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Gemini Gems (Jewelry Boxes, Stands, etc.), 1980-1981; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Hasah El Agizy - Egyptian Jewelry, undated; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Imports, Exports General Merchandise (Statues), 1975-1977; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Intrasonic Records - Fred Elias, 1979-1980; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Jalal Takesh, 1977-1979; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - John Kessler of New York, Inc., 1973; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - John J. Madison Company, Inc. (little animals), 1978; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Joseph Nicholas (cards), 1978; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Kayboys Paper Co., 1978; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - KCL Corporation, 1975-1976; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Leonard Dorn Company, 1979; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Limoges Creations Ltd., 1979; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - L.S. Creations (Earrings), 1976; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Mid-East Bazaar (Records), 1978; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Mid-East Manufacturing Company (Cymbals/Tambourines), 1975; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Monitor Recordings, Inc., 1975-1980; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - National Wholesale Music Corporation, 1973-1976; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Oceanic Imports, Inc. (Jewelry), 1974; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Ohio Bag Corporation, 1976; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Oriental Imports, 1974; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Panos Papantoniou (Gold Jewelry), 1973; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Paris and Company (Costume Jewelry), 1976; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Peters International, Inc., 1976-1977; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Rashid Sales and K & K Records, 1973-1981; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Record Distributors, 1978; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Samiha's Night Club IBIS, 1976-1977; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Sarpat Sales Company (Zills), 1975-1976; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Superior Jewelry (Snake Bracelets), 1979; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Twelveth of May, Inc. (Indian Jewelry), 1976-1978; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - The Candle Shop, 1976-1977; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - United Artists Records of America, 1979; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Wood'N Wax Co. (Figuerine Candles), 1976; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Publicity and dance materials, 1964-2010; Series 1 Subseries 3
    This subseries includes material related to Adriana Miller's career as a belly dancer, as a teacher, and later as an expert in the field. It contains programs, flyers, articles, correspondence, dancer biographies, event information, and teaching materials. The different administrative files within this subseries represent those items that Adriana originally grouped together within folder and binders.The dates covered include 1964-2010.
    Arranged alphabetically
    - Administrative File - Articles, Programs, Press Releases, and Handwritten Notes, 1976-2010; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Administrative File - Articles, Programs, Flyers, and Photographs [1/2], 1965-2006; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Administrative File - Articles, Programs, Flyers, and Photographs [2/2], 1965-2006; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Administrative File - Articles, Flyers, and Press Releases, 1964-2003; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Administrative File - Articles, Programs, Flyers, and Teaching Materials [1/3], 1975-1992; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Administrative File - Articles, Programs, Flyers, and Teaching Materials [2/3], 1975-1992; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Administrative File - Articles, Programs, Flyers, and Teaching Materials [3/3], 1975-1992; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Administrative File - Articles, Handwritten Notes, and Miscellaneous, 1967-2002; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Administrative File - Flyers, Contracts, and Correspondence, 1993-1998; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Administrative File - Flyers, Programs, Contracts, Articles, and Biographies, 1966-2013; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Administrative File - Handwritten Notes about Shows, Dancers, Flyers, and Miscellaneous, 1993-2001; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Administrative File - Programs, Flyers, and Reviews, 1976-2007; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Administrative File - Programs, Flyers, and Press Releases, 1993-1994; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Administrative File - Programs and Newspaper Clippings, 1978-1980; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Adriana's Books in Studio, undated; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Adriana Signature Book, 1998-2000; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 15, Item 1)
    - Annual Award Program AMEMCA, 1995-2002; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Arabesque Magazine (Bobby Farrah), undated; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Bazaar, 1978; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Biography of Morocco (Carolina Varga Dinicu, 1982-1992; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Bobby's Workshop, 1980-1981; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Churches and Temples, 1977; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Consultants File, 2003; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence to Dahlena, 1979; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Correspondece - General, 1997-2010; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Costume Workshop Materials, undated; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Dance Oriental Portfolio (Pictures/Bio), 1992; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Dance Research, undated; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Dancer Biographies, 1992-1998; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Email Correspondence, 2000-2001; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Flyers, 2010; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Giza Academy Awards, 1999-2004; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Habiba Biography, 1996; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Meeting Materials for Shows, 1992-1994; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Mike Sarkissian Biography, 1979, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Montgomery County College Rockville, MD, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1971-2001; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Organizing for Pro Dancer Contracts, Constitution, etc., 1977; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Pamela Jones (Charissa) Biography, 1978; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Patricia Rae Marggraf Biography, undated; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Places Performed or Associated With, 1973-2001; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Press Release (Letters), 1976-1996; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 14, Folder 5.)
    - Professional Dancers, undated; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Productions and Theatrical Agency, 1998; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Programs and Flyers [1/2], 1978-2003; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Programs and Flyers [2/2], 1978-2003; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Programs and Flyers, 1993-2003; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Provided Agencies and Advocacy Organizations, 1995-1999; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Radio-TV Networks, 1975; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Real Earth Productions - Contract with Ray Schmitt, 1998-1999; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Shows, 1979; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Turquoise Finger Cymbals, 1991; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - YWCA and WMCA, undated; Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Photographs, 1950-2002; MS2005 Series 2
  This series contains black and white photographs of Adriana Miller's performances as a dancer, as well as images of her students. It also includes images of various other belly dancers. This material dates from 1950-2002.
  Arranged in no particular order.
  - Adriana Miller standing in a grass field, bushes in background, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Studio portrait of Adriana Miller and seated on a cloth-covered stool, curtain in background, 1950-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Studio portraits of Adriana Miller, 1950-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Studio portraits of Adriana Miller, 1950-1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Studio portraits of Adriana Miller, 1950-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Studio portraits of Adriana Miller, 1950-1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Adriana Miller dancing the Torrentela Italian dance at a Stanley Brown Dance School recital, Boston, MA, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 8" x 7 ½ " photocopy of a photograph of Adriana Miller performing at the Suez Club in Washington, DC, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Adriana Miller performing at the Suez Club in Washington, DC, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Adriana Miller performing at the Suez Club in Washington, DC, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Adriana Miller performing at the Acropolis Lounge and Restaurant in Baltimore, MD, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Adriana Miller performing at the Acropolis Lounge and Restaurant in Baltimore, MD, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Adriana Miller performing at the Acropolis Lounge and Restaurant in Baltimore, MD, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Adriana Miller performing at the Acropolis Lounge and Restaurant in Baltimore, MD, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Adriana Miller performing at the Acropolis Lounge and Restaurant in Baltimore, MD, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Adriana Miller performing, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 5" x 7" color photograph and 8" x 10" color photocopy of Adriana Miller on the cover of an Eddie "Sheik" Kochak and Hakki Obadia album, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Studio portraits of Adriana Miller, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Studio portraits of Adriana Miller, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Studio portraits of Adriana Miller, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Adriana Miller performing at the Torch Club in Baltimore, MD, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Adriana Miller performing at the Torch Club in Baltimore, MD, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Studio portraits of Adriana Miller, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Studio portraits of Adriana Miller, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Studio portraits of Adriana Miller, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 8 ½" x 11" photocopy of a studio portrait of Adriana Miller, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Adriana Miller teaching in Cheverly, MD, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Adriana Miller teaching in Cheverly, MD, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Adriana Miller teaching in Cheverly, MD, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Adriana Miller teaching in Cheverly, MD, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Adriana Miller teaching in Cheverly, MD, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 10" x 7" photocopy of a photograph of an Adriana Miller performance that appeared in US World News, June 26, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Adriana Miller and Abrahim Farrar, 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Adriana Miller performing at private events, 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Adriana Miller performing at private events, 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Adriana Miller performing at Walter Reed Army Medical Center, 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Adriana Miller performing at Walter Reed Army Medical Center, 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Adriana Miller performing at Walter Reed Army Medical Center, 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Adriana Miller performing at Walter Reed Army Medical Center, 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Adriana Miller performing at Walter Reed Army Medical Center, 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Adriana Twirling, undated; Series 2 (Box 16, Item 1)
  - Adriana Dancing, undated; Series 2 (Box 16, Item 2)
  - Various Photos of a Belly Dancer in a Picture Frame, undated; Series 2 (Box 16, Item 3)
  - Pictures of Alvin Alley and Spanish Dancing, undated; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Pictures of Dancers-Musician Bio and Flyers, 1989-1994; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Adriana Miller and other Belly Dancers [1/2], undated; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Adriana Miller and other Belly Dancers [2/2], undated; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Adriana Miller and other Performers, Articles, and Flyers [1/2], 1968-2002; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Adriana Miller and other Performers, Articles, and Flyers [2/2], 1968-2002; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Various Photographs of Adriana Miller and other Dancers, undated; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Photograph Album: Adriana and Troupe, 1970; Series 2 (Box 16, Item 4)
  - Photograph Album: American University Adriana's Mecca of M.E. Dance Troupe, undated; Series 2 (Box 16, Item 5)
  - Photograph Album: Adriana and Troope, undated; Series 2 (Box 16, Item 6)
  - Photo Album, undated; Series 2 (Box 16, Item 7)
  - Photograph Album: Adriana and Troope, undated; Series 2 (Box 16, Item 8)
  - Photograph Album, undated; Series 2 (Box 16, Item 9)
  - Large Cut Out Image of Adriana Miller, undated; Series 2 (Map-folder 1)
- Audio and visual materials, 1961-2002; MS2005 Series 3
  This series contains several audio casettes and video casettes of Adriana Miller dance performances. The years covered are 1961-2002.
  - Audiocassette: Adriana, undated; Series 3 (Box 9, Item 3)
  - Audiocassette:The Best of Belly Dancing, performed by Eddie "The Sheik" Kochak and Hakki Odadia, vol. 1, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Audiocassette:Golden Hits For Belly Dancing, performed by Eddie "The Sheik" Kochak, 1987 ca. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Audiocassette: Live Music Farush at Salaam, undated; Series 3 (Box 9, Item 4)
  - Audiocassette:Strictly Ya Habibi Belly Dancing USA, performed by Eddie "The Sheik" Kochak and Hakki Obadia, vols. 1-6, 1983 ca. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Audiocassette: Unmarked Memorex cassette, undated; Series 3 (Box 9, Item 5)
  - Reel: Adriana Miller Oriental, undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Item 4)
  - Reel: Arabic Recordings, undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Item 5)
  - Reel: Dance Routine with Fred and Emile, undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Item 6)
  - Reel: Greek Music, undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Item 7)
  - Reel: Greek Music, undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Item 8)
  - Reel: Half hour Dance of Adriana from the Night Club Port Said, Washington, D.C., undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Item 9)
  - Reel: (Lebanon) Arabic Folk Folk Music, undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Item 10)
  - Reel: Me Singing, undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Item 11)
  - Reel: Music by John T., undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Item 12)
  - Reel: Music from Algies Club for Teaching, undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Item 13)
  - Reel: Mystical Temptations and All Ports East, undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Item 14)
  - Reel: One Hour Broadcast on Savas Sapounakis Greek Radio Hour WFAX, Adriana's Solo Dance, 1961 August 06; Series 3 (Box 11, Item 15)
  - Reel: The Soul of Mexico, 1964 July 25; Series 3 (Box 11, Item 16)
  - Reel: Stanley Bnowus, undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Item 17)
  - Reel: Unmarked Total Range Recording Tape, undated; Series 3 (Box 9, Item 1)
  - Reel: Unmarked Scotch 90 tape, undated; Series 3 (Box 9, Item 2)
  - Videocassettes: 2nd Gala with Bobby, 1993 October 22; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 1)
  - Videocassettes: 4th ME (Middle East) Awards, 1996 December 08; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 2)
  - Videocassettes: Adriana 3rd Gala, 1994 May 21; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 3)
  - Videocassettes: Adriana 7th Awards Alexes Taverna, 2001 November 17; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 4)
  - Videocassettes: Adriana's 9th Awards pt 2, 2003 November 16; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 5)
  - Videocassettes: Adriana's Dance Company Troup Cyra Antonia MRC Baltimore, 1997; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 6)
  - Videocassettes: Adriana Duplicate Interviews, undated; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 7)
  - Videocassettes: Adriana Gala, 1995; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 8)
  - Videocassettes: Adriana's Greek Folk Workshop, 1994 February 26; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 9)
  - Videocassettes: Adriana's Let's Go Greek Workshop, 1994 April 16; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 10)
  - Videocassettes: Adriana Memories Teaching Clip - No Audio, 1970; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 11)
  - Videocassettes: Adriana MRC Rehearsal, 1996; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 12)
  - Videocassettes: Adriana's MRC Show, 1996 March 26; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 13)
  - Videocassettes: Adriana Photos Emin Gundig Interview, undated; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 14)
  - Videocassettes: Adriana's Recital with Geroge Abdo, 1979 December 01; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 15)
  - Videocassettes: Adriana: Shadows on Yellow Silk, 1997; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 16)
  - Videocassettes:Adriana: Shadows on Yellow Silk, Real Earth Productions, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Videocassettes: A.M.E.M. Award with Bobby, 1993; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 17)
  - Videocassettes: Cretan Dances H Lavedia Ton Kritikan Horon, undated; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 18)
  - Videocassettes: Gala Reviews and Reunion Tape 1, 1992 December 01; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 19)
  - Videocassettes: George Washington Univ - Adriana Interview, 1998 February 04; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 20)
  - Videocassettes: HairFlex Instructional Video, undated; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 21)
  - Videocassettes: Laurel Victoria Gray Workshop, 1994 July 23; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 22)
  - Videocassettes: Linda Seidel Natural Cover, undated; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 23)
  - Videocassettes: Live with George Abdo and Adriana, 1979; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 24)
  - Videocassettes: Middle Eastern-Mediterranean Gala Review Tape 2, 1992 December 01; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 25)
  - Videocassettes: MRC Dance Program Unedited Dub, undated; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 26)
  - Videocassettes: Paris Video, undated; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 27)
  - Videocassettes: Salome' Presents Orientale Dance Symposium XVIII Ergallis Kakias & Najawa Al Qamar Galbreath Pavillion, Columbus, OH, 2002 October 12; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 28)
  - Videocassettes:Screening and post-screening discussion at the screening of Adriana: Shadows on Yellow Silk held in the Marvin Center at the George Washington University, 1998 February 04 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Videocassettes: Sultanin Gozdesi Oryantal Bale, undated; Series 3 (Box 10, Item 29)